（店員）いらっしゃいませー
ごゆっくり ご覧くださーい
Thank you for shopping with us.
Take your time looking around.
（烈子(れつこ)）あっ…
あっ それ かわいいですよねー
サイズなかったら出しますよー
Oh, that's cute!
Let me know if you can't find your size.
あっ 大丈夫でーす
I'm OK.
We provide service with a smile,
even for those just browsing.
ひやかしのお客様も―
笑顔で対応させて
いただいておりまーす
ご試着したいときは
言ってくださいねー
Tell me if you want to try anything on.
（烈子）大丈夫でーす
I'm OK.
ごゆっくり ご覧くださーい
Take your time!
Let me take my time already!
RAGE
♪～
～♪
（レジを打つ音）
（店員）靴下３足セットのみの
お買い上げで 1080円になりまーす
Your purchase of just a three-pair
set of socks comes to 1080 yen.
ポイントカードお持ちですかー？
Do you have a points card?
ああ… いえ…
No.
With our current promotion,
you'll get double points - a great deal.
ただいま ポイント２倍
キャンペーン中なので―
お得ですよー
（烈子）えっと… あの…
Well...
（烈子）めんどくさいな
次 いつ来るか分かんないしな
What a pain.
I don't even know when I'll be back.
お作りしますかー？
Would you like to apply for one?
（烈子）あの… け… 結構です
No, thank you.
はい？
Sorry?
Would you like to apply for one?
お作りしますかー？
ああ… じゃあ…
OK...
かしこまりましたー
Certainly!
それでは こちらの記入欄に―
OK, just fill this out
with your name and email address.
お名前と携帯のメールアドレスを
ご記入いただいて
She doesn't need a card.
（プー子(こ)）カードいりませーん
えっ？
行こ 烈子
Let's go, Retsuko.
プー子！？
Puko?
I work part-time in Japan, for six months.
（プー子）
半年 日本でバイトして―
お金が たまったら
あとの半年は海外
Once I've saved enough money,
I spend the rest of the year abroad.
お金がなくなったら
また日本で半年バイトして海外
If I run out of money,
I come home and do it again.
みたいな生活 高校出てから
ずーっと繰り返しててさ
That's what I've been doing
since we got out of high school.
へえー そんなことしてたんだ
すごいね
Wow! So that's what you've been up to.
Amazing.
すごくないって
Not really...
おかげで いまだに
定職にも就いてない
It's the reason
I still haven't got a steady job.
でも プー子らしいよ
But that's so you.
It sounds fun. I envy you.
楽しそうで羨ましい
そう？
Really?
烈子は働いてんだよね？
You have a job, don't you?
うん 普通にＯＬ
Yeah. I'm a regular office lady.
What kind of work is it?
どんな仕事？
一応 商社
It's a trading firm.
そこで経理の仕事してる
I do accounting there.
すごいじゃん！
That's amazing!
烈子は昔っから
真面目で堅実だもんね
But, then, you've always been
the responsible sort.
（烈子）
っていうか 私って そんな真面目？
Really? You think I'm responsible?
だって 烈子ってさ―
Because you're, like,
the kind who never taps "I agree"
to an app's terms of service
携帯アプリの
長ったらしい利用規約を―
端から端まで読み尽くすまで―
without reading the whole thing, right?
絶対に 同意ボタン
押さないタイプでしょ？
普通に押すよ
No, I don't do that.
The type who's already
saving money for retirement.
この年で老後のために
貯金してるタイプ
してないよ
No, not yet.
（プー子）服屋で何も買わずに
帰るのは悪いような気がして―
You're the type
who buys three pairs of socks
because you feel bad for leaving
without buying anything.
とりあえず ３足 千円の靴下
買っちゃうタイプ
当たってる…
That's true.
ほら 真面目じゃん
See? You are responsible.
ま… 真面目なのかな…
よく分かんないけど
I guess I might be. I'm not sure, though.
It's a compliment!
褒めてんのよ
それが烈子の いいとこだし
That's a good thing about you.
ただ そこが ちょっと
心配でもあるんだけど
But it's also something
I'm a bit worried about.
えっ？
（プー子）人生 楽しめてる？
Are you enjoying life?
何かさ―
I'm not gonna lie...
顔 疲れてるよ
You look... pretty wiped out.
（目覚ましの音）
（烈子）うう…
うう…
FOR THOSE WHO WANT A JOB CHANGE
うん…
I'm so busy.
（坪根(つぼね)）ハアー 忙しい 忙しい
あら？
ちょっと疲れた顔してるわね
Goodness! You look a bit tired.
ええ… まあ… ちょっと…
Yeah... a little.
Oh, dear. Are you sleeping properly?
Are you eating?
あらー ちゃんと寝てる？
食べてる？
私 ちょっと
あなたに―
Maybe I've been leaning too hard on you.
甘え過ぎてたかも
しれないわね
えっ？
Huh?
あなたを信頼して
ついつい仕事 振っちゃうの
I share my work with you
because I trust you.
ごめんなさいね
Forgive me.
坪根さん…
Miss Tsubone...
私 最近
健康のためにジョギングしてるのよ
Lately, I've been jogging to stay healthy.
はっ？
Huh?
これが最初のうちは つらくてねえ
It was hard at first.
But I kept at it,
and it gradually became easier.
それでも続けてると
だんだん楽になってくるの
Muscles build over time, right?
きっと必要な筋肉が
ついてくるのね
はあ…
Right...
（坪根）つまり！
In other words...
you haven't built up the muscles
for your job yet!
あんたは まだ仕事の筋肉が
足りてないってこと
（烈子）ええっ！？
（坪根）はい！ どんどん頑張って
筋肉つけちゃって！
There! Keep working hard
and build up those muscles!
You don't have time to be tired!
We're understaffed right now!
疲れてる暇なんて ないわよ！
この時期は人手が足りないの！
（トン）フン！ フン！
（烈子）あの…
I can see someone
who could help over there, though...
あそこに人手が
余ってるように見えるんですけど…
あれは仕事！
That's... his job!
はあ…
Oh.
あー とっても忙しい！
Man, am I busy!
（小宮(こみや)）トン部長！
Director Ton,
sorry to bother you while you're busy--
お忙しいところ
申し訳ありませ～ん！
I'm in the middle of something.
今 手が離せん
お仕事を増やしてしまい
心苦しいのですが―
It pains me to increase
your workload, sir,
but could I have a bit of your time?
少々お時間を
頂けますでしょうか？
There's something I want you to see.
是非 見ていただきたいものが…
フン 見せてみろ
What have you got?
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much!
北茨城(きたいばらき)にあるゴルフ場なんですが…
It's a golf course in Northern Ibaraki...
（トン）うむ
with unbeatable prices!
（小宮）値段も手ごろです
（トン）うむ
There's more...
しかも…
敷地内に温泉施設もあります
There's a hot spring on the property.
（トン）うむ～！
小宮よ 忙しくなりそうだな
Komiya,
we've got our work cut out for us.
過労で倒れてしまいそうです
I think I might collapse from overwork!
（トン･小宮）
あー とっても忙しい！
Man, are we busy!
♪～
Lightning, grant me your vengeance!
Hit my boss's golf club - find your mark!
Hit the flunky's golf club
Find your mark!
Lightning, grant me your vengeance!
Hit the witch's head as she runs!
Strike them down!
（デス烈子の荒い息）
よし 戻って仕事しよ
OK, back to work.
（フェネ子(こ)）烈子 どうした？
Retsuko, what's wrong?
（烈子）えっ？ 何が？
With what?
（フェネ子）うーん
多分 烈子のおばあちゃんって―
I was just thinking, your grandma
probably looks like you do right now.
こんな顔なんだろうなー
って顔してる
えっ…
ああっ！ 狭山(さやま)の ばあちゃん！
It's my grandma in Sayama!
（ハイ田(だ)）烈子 まさか あの仕事
全部 終わらせたのか？
Retsuko, don't tell me
you finished all that paperwork...?
（烈子）うん 根性で終わらせた
Yeah, I pushed through it.
（フェネ子･ハイ田）
おおー 真面目
Whoa! Responsible...
（烈子）それ 友達にも言われた
That's just what my friend told me.
私って そんな真面目？
Am I really that serious?
えっ？ ああ…
まあ…
Yeah...
真面目で堅実だよね
Serious and reliable.
携帯アプリの
利用規約を―
The type who reads an app's
terms of service before tapping "I agree".
端から端まで
読み尽くすまで―
同意ボタン
押さないタイプ
（烈子）それ 友達にも言われた
My friend said that, too.
The type who starts saving early
for old age.
この年で老後のために
貯金してるタイプ
（烈子）それも言われた
She said that, too.
（フェネ子･ハイ田）
服屋で何も買わずに
帰るのは―
The type who buys some socks to avoid
leaving without making a purchase.
悪いような気がして―
とりあえず３足 千円の
靴下 買っちゃうタイプ
だから何で分かるの？
Stop freaking me out!
だって 相手に 何か
期待されると―
Because you're the type who is desperate
to live up to expectations.
身を削ってクソ真面目に
応えちゃうタイプじゃん
ああ… なるほど… そうかも…
I see. Maybe so.
The type that self-destructs
from doing their boss's job for them.
会社では その性格が災いして―
上司に仕事を押しつけられて
自滅するタイプ
ああ…
小心者で
あるがゆえに―
A greenhorn robot caught up
in corporate expectations.
企業の思惑に
からめ捕られたロボット
あああ…
An obedient corporate slave
who waits in line to die from overwork.
（フェネ子）過労死を待つ列に
自分から並ぶ従順な社畜
（烈子）うう…
ブラック企業を
肥え太らせるための餌
The fodder fattening up
sweatshop companies.
おい フェネ子
そのへんにしとけよ
Fenneko, I think you should stop there.
（フェネ子）
あっ ごめん 言い過ぎた
Oh! Sorry. I said too much.
（ハイ田）うーん つまり あれだ
In other words... Oh, yes.
烈子は いい子ってことだよ なっ？
It means Retsuko is a "good girl". Right?
まあね
I guess.
だけど
ずっと いい子でいるのは―
But being a "good girl" all the time is...
tiring, isn't it?
疲れるよね
RAGE
♪～
Judgment from everyone!
And you tell me that I'm just a drone!
Bending over backwards for the boss-man!
Plain vanilla life 'til the moment I die!
Team players lose!
（烈子）ってことなんだよね…
That's how it is.
Probably...
多分…
（烈子）いつも かっこいいな
They always look cool.
Like working women,
overflowing with confidence...
自信に満ちた働く女性って感じ
私みたいに中途半端じゃ―
I'm just a pushover.
この人たちみたいに
キラキラした存在には―
I could never shine like those two do.
なれないんだろうな
かといって―
But then, I can't wing it
like Puko does, either.
プー子みたいに
自由に生きることもできない
（烈子）ハア…
（ゴリ）超ラッキー
Lucky me...
（鷲美(わしみ)）どうしたの？
What do you mean?
さっき擦れ違った子
ずっと会いたいなって思ってたの
That girl we just passed -
I was hoping to see her all day.
朝の占いで 黄色が
ラッキーカラーだって言ってたから
My fortune this morning said
yellow would be my lucky color.
（鷲美）よかったわね
That's nice.
（烈子）ハア…
（メールの受信音）
ARE YOU DONE WITH WORK?
CAN WE MEET NOW?
BAR
（プー子）ういーす お疲れー！
Cheers! Long day, huh?
You too!
（烈子）お疲れさま！
Nah, I'm not really tired.
No job and all...
って私は別に疲れてないんだけどさ
働いてないし
プハー
C'mon, Retsuko. Down the hatch!
ほら 烈子も グーッと空けな
（烈子）でさ 職場の飲み会で
トン部長に お酌させられるでしょ
So,
you know how I have to pour drinks
for Director Ton at work parties?
で ビールをこうやって注ぐとさ…
So I was pouring the beer like this and...
注ぐときは ラベルを
上に向けるのが礼儀だろうが
You're supposed to pour
with the bottle label-side up.
Don't you even know that much?
そんなことも知らねえのか！
That is the problem with young women.
これだから若い女はよ！
何だ それ？
What the hell!
思うでしょ？
ほんと意味 分かんない！
Right? It doesn't make any sense!
そんなオヤジ 昭和の時代に
絶滅したんじゃないの？
Didn't old men like that
die off in the '80s?
うちには まだ いるんだよ…
Not at our office.
Sockets have started to remind me
of Director Ton's face.
最近 コンセントプラグ見ても
トン部長の顔 思い出しちゃってさ
ハッハッハッハッ… うける
That's funny!
（烈子）いつか あいつの顔面に
バシーッと―
Someday, I want to slap
a resignation letter right in his face.
退職願を
たたきつけてやりたいんだよね
それが私の夢
That's my dream.
アッハッハッ…
烈子って 話すと 面白いよね
It's really fun to talk with you.
あっ ごめん 私ばっか話してるね
Oh, sorry.
I'm only talking about myself, aren't I?
What are you going to do now?
Will you be in Japan for a while?
プー子は これから どうするの？
しばらく日本にいる？
（プー子）うーん…
んっ んん
実は今度 日本でビジネス
始めてみようかなって思ってて
Actually, I was thinking I might
start a business here in Japan.
ビジネス！？
A business?
まあ 先輩と一緒にやるんだけどね
Well, me and a friend together.
何するの？
What are you doing?
輸入雑貨屋
An imported goods store.
（烈子）輸入雑貨屋！
An imported goods store!
海外から商品 買い付けてさ
We'll bring back products from overseas.
ほら 私 向こうにも
たくさん友達いるし
I've got plenty of friends out there.
自分たちのセンスで 何か
面白いこと できないかなって
With our tastes, I bet
we could do something interesting.
何それ…
Seriously?
That's super great!
超すてきなんだけど
やめてよ
Oh, stop it. It's not that big of a deal.
別に そんな大したもんじゃ…
最高！ 超羨ましい！
It is! I am super jealous!
じゃ 一緒にやる？
Well... You want in?
えっ？
What?
ちょっと待って…
Wait a second.
Stop. I just got really shaky.
やめて 今 本当グラッと来た
Really?
ほんと？
じゃあ やろうよ
Then let's do it.
（烈子）いや～…
や… やっぱり会社あるし…
But I've got the company...
Why don't you quit?
辞めちゃえば？
（プー子）
烈子だったら 経理もできるじゃん
Retsuko, you can do accounting, can't you?
My friend and I
are the happy-go-lucky types,
それに 私も先輩も―
ちゃらんぽらんな
性格してるからさ―
so someone responsible like you
would make up for what we lack.
真面目な烈子と足りないところ
補い合ってさ
（烈子）何それ…
Seriously?
You can go overseas to make deals!
（プー子）買い付けのときは
経費で海外も行けちゃうよ
Seriously?
（烈子）何それ…
So? Wanna do it?
（プー子）ねえ 一緒にやろ？
（烈子）
何それ 何それ 何それ 何それ
Seriously, seriously, seriously?
Seriously?
何それ～！
ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT
（烈子）フン！
フン！
何やってんだ？
What are you doing?
（烈子）うっ…
うう… 運動です
Exercise.
（トン）あっ？
（烈子）
エヘヘ… 掃除がてら 朝の運動を…
Cleaning and exercising
at the same time...
（トン）フン！
気楽なもんだな
Well, aren't you carefree.
運動したいなら
メニューを追加してやる
I've got the perfect exercise for you.
Polish my clubs.
俺のクラブも磨いとけ
あっ はーい
Yes, sir.
傷つけんなよ
Don't scratch them.
あー とっても忙しい！
Man, am I busy!
You're the carefree one.
（烈子）気楽なもんね
This is practice for the near future,
このフォームが
そう遠くない未来―
when I smack you in the face
with a resignation letter.
退職願をあんたの顔面に―
たたきつけるための
練習だとも知らずに
辞めてやる…
I'm gonna quit.
I'm gonna quit...
辞めてやる…
this awful job.
こんな会社！
Well, thanks in advance.
じゃ お願いね
（烈子）バシーッと辞めてやる！
ワッハッハッ…
I'm gonna quit the crap out of it!
Subtitle translation: John Haguewood
♪～
～♪